翻译：草草  CS漫画家小明  Arie  某羽  王大可  香茗小焙
翻译：鱼小姐啦  Reginamoon  菲力   校对：潇湘月影  油炸电风扇
时间轴：aaaBao  永远的永远  今  阿丹
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第四季   第十二集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
吉拉德教授
Professor gerard.
-我来请你帮个忙  -我不会答应的
- I came to ask for a favor. - The answer is no.
所以我带了这个来
Which is why I brought this.
你知道了
You know.
你高谈阔论
And you talk a big game,
但你其实也只是一个普通人
but you're just as human as everyone else,
你这自以为是的混蛋
you smug son of a bitch.
路易
Louis.
-你怎么来了  -我要走了
- What are you doing here? - Leaving.
这样我就不用看着你们两个骗子了
That way I don't have to look at either one of you two liars.
天呐  他知道了
Oh, my God, he knows.
他不仅知道了
He doesn't just know.
还成了冠名合伙人
He's a name partner.
她跑到我面前对我撒谎
She came to me and lied to my face.
她这么做是为了保护我
She did it to protect me
我打算继续打击她
I'm gonna keep hammering on her
直到你崩溃
until you break.
新的名字带来新的开始
With a new name comes a new beginning.
敬我们最新的冠名合伙人吧  路易·利特
Here's to our newest name partner, Louis Litt.
路易掌握了你的把柄
Louis has something on you.
丹尼尔·哈德曼挪用律所资金
Daniel Hardman embezzled money from the firm,
我为他遮掩了
and I covered it up.
你之前为什么不能信任我  告诉我
Why couldn't you trust me with that before?
因为我不知道你会有什么反应
Because I didn't know how you'd react,
杰西卡
Jessica,
我会帮你保密
your secret is safe with me.
我以为我们现在不搞屋顶谈话了
I thought we were done with rooftop conversations.
有些事得私下说
Some things require privacy.
这话自你半夜策划
I haven't heard you say that
夺下施密特-高登-范·戴克律所就没听你说过了
since the midnight coup of Schmidt, Gordon, and Van Dyke.
闹够了吗
You done?
我不是在开玩笑
It wasn't a joke.
我的事也不是玩笑
Neither is this.
我告诉杰夫·马龙我帮忙
I told Jeff Malone I helped cover up
掩盖了丹尼尔·哈德曼的挪用公款
Daniel Hardman's embezzlement.
你为什么要提那件旧事
Why the hell would you open that time capsule?
因为他知道我们
Because he knew the explanation
给其他合伙人做出的关于路易的解释就是鬼扯
we gave the partners about Louis was bullshit,
我只能告诉他点什么
and I had to tell him something.
你可以告诉他那不关他的事
You could've told him it was none of his business.
哈维  我叫你上来
Harvey, I didn't bring you here
不是为了寻求感情建议
to get relationship advice.
我只是叫你上来告诉你我做了什么
I brought you here to tell you what I did
以防这事哪天提起
in case it ever came up.
才不是
No, you didn't.
你叫我来是因为这下
You brought me here because now
你得让路易配合你的说辞
you have to get Louis to back you,
你也知道我说了不好听的忠言
and you knew you'd be mad at me
你就会生我气
when I told you what you didn't want to hear.
没错  我不想听
You're right. I don't want to hear it.
你觉得如果我告诉路易
How do you think it's gonna go
我的感情前途握在他手里
when I tell Louis he holds
会怎么样呢
the fate of my relationship in his hands?
你觉得等马龙提起路易敲诈的事
How do you think it's gonna go
又会怎么样呢
the first time Malone brings up Louis' blackmail?
我不管
I don't care.
我告诉你吧
Well, I'll tell you how it's gonna go.
路易会回过头来
Louis is gonna look back
贼眉鼠眼地说  "挪用公款
with his beady little eyes and say, "Embezzlement?
我才不是因为那个成了冠名合伙人呢"
That's not how I got my name on the wall."
到时还是要天下大乱
And the shit's gonna hit the fan anyway.
告诉你
You know what?
你有时候真混蛋
You can be a real son of a bitch.
是啊  但你与其生我气
Yeah, but instead of being pissed at me,
还不如对着镜子生自己气
why don't you take a look in the mirror?
因为我们伸出了橄榄枝
Because we held out an olive branch,
但路易一听说这事
and after Louis hears this,
他就会夺下那根橄榄枝
he's gonna take that branch
用它抽死我们
and beat the shit out of us with it.
皮尔逊·斯佩克特·利特
路易
Louis.
吉拉德教授  你怎么来了
Professor Gerard? What are you doing here?
我有件小小的法律事务要处理
I've got a small legal matter to attend to.
我能帮上忙吗
Well, is it anything I can help you with?
其实  我是来找哈维的
Actually, I'm here to speak with Harvey.
我明白
I understand.
你是要找冠名合伙人
You're looking for a name partner.
在这里是看不见
Well, you can't quite see it from here,
但如果你倒退十步
but if you walk back about ten feet,
往左边扫一眼
take a gander to your left,
你就会看到我得到了认可...
you'll see I've gotten a little recognition--
恭喜你  但我说了
I appreciate that, but as I said,
我是来找哈维的
I'm here to speak with Harvey.
我们要谈谈杰西卡给路易的
So are we gonna talk about that little welcome speech
欢迎致辞吗
that Jessica made for Louis?
我们不用谈
We don't have to talk about it
因为路易不会认栽的
because Louis isn't going to accept it.
为什么
Why not?
因为他永远不可能
Because it'll be a cold day in hell
承认我是冰人  他只是小牛
when he can accept being Maverick to my Iceman.
冰人  小牛
著名电影《壮志凌云》中主角代号
你是说反了吧
Don't--don't you mean Iceman to your Maverick?
没有
No, I don't.
你比起小牛更想做冰人吗
You actually want to be Iceman over Maverick?
-谁拿到奖杯了  -谁是更好的飞行员
- Who got the trophy? - Who's the better pilot?
-拿奖杯的那个  -错
- The one who got the trophy. - Wrong.
因为最后  小牛救了冰人
Because in the end, Maverick saved Iceman,
否则  奖杯男现在就躺在
and if he hadn't, trophy boy would be sitting
印度洋海底了
on the bottom of the Indian Ocean right now.
那他也还是更厉害
Where he'd still be the man.
那是你的看法
According to you.
我的看法是唯一重要的看法
According to me is the only "according to" that matters.
又来了
Here we go.
或许吧  但我的看法是
Maybe, but according to me,
毒蛇才是电影里的真英雄
Viper was the real hero of that film.
怎么了
What?
你以为我太老没看过《壮志凌云》吗
You think I'm too old to know Top Gun?
我认为
What I think is,
你不该进我办公室
you have no business being in my office.
我们要当着你初级律师的面吵吗
Are we gonna do this in front of your associate?
我们不用当着谁的面做什么
We don't have to do anything in front of anybody.
你出去就好
You just have to go.
哈维
Harvey...
我需要个律师
I need a lawyer.
路易的办公室就在走廊那头
Louis' office is down the hall.
我不要路易
I don't want Louis.
-我要你  -真搞笑
- I want you. - That's funny.
你上次看见我时  你说
The last time you saw me, you told me
我不配在你的象牙塔里做律师
I wasn't fit to practice law in your ivory tower.
我是说
What I told you was,
你会为赢官司而放弃道德
is that you'll sacrifice ethics for wins,
可我现在不在象牙塔里
and right now I'm not in my ivory tower,
我需要赢官司
and I need a win.
我就知道
I knew it.
你跟别人没什么两样
You're just like everybody else.
不择手段是卑劣的
The ends don't justify the means
除非是你自己有危险
until it's your ass on the line.
你以为我喜欢向你求助吗
Do you think I like asking you for help?
我觉得自由铁路公司的事一定要你命了
I think this Liberty Rail thing must have you by the balls.
你知道了
So you know.
我知道他家火车脱轨后
I know after their train derailed,
你被指派去评估受害者赔付方案
you were appointed to assess the victims' compensation formula,
我知道此事后
and I know after you did,
有部分受害人雇了律师
some of those victims hired a lawyer
展开调查
and opened an investigation.
那你也该知道他们什么都没发现
Then you also know they found nothing.
那问题是  你为什么要来
Then the question is, why are you here?
我宣布改变赔付方案那天
The TSA found $25,000 in my luggage
运输安全管理局在我的行李里找到了两万五千块
the day I announced I was changing the formula.
所以你被指控受贿了
So now you're being accused of accepting a bribe.
但我没受贿
Which I did not do.
祝你能证明这一点  教授
Well, good luck proving that, Professor,
因为我不会帮你的
because it won't be with my help.
我看错你了  斯佩克特先生
I was wrong about you, Mr. Specter.
我没想到你会因为你不喜欢客户
I never thought that you wouldn't represent somebody
而拒绝代理
just because you didn't like them.
那你又错了
Well, you're wrong again.
我不喜欢你  但我之所以不接你的案子
I don't like you, but I'm not representing you
是因为你做了见不得光的事
because you did something shady,
我不愿为了博你喜欢
and I'm not screwing over crash victims
而去折磨那些受害者
for the likes of you.
你知道我没有做那种事
You know I didn't do this.
我只知道你是自己跑过来的
What I know is you showed yourself in.
现在你也可以自己出去
You can show yourself out.
我不想在吉拉德面前说什么
Hey, I didn't want to say anything in front of Gerard,
但你有没有想过
but has it occurred to you
如果你不接这个案子你就是个傻瓜
that you're an idiot if you don't take this case?
去年  你怕他发现你的事
Last year, you were shitting yourself
怕到都要尿裤子了
he'd find out about you,
现在你却认为我们应该跟他合作
and now you think we should work with him?
不  我当时不是担心他发现
No, I wasn't worried he'd find out.
而是担心路易发现
I was worried about Louis.
吉拉德那时都没有正眼看我一下
Gerard didn't bat an eye at me back then,
刚才也没看
and he didn't just now.
但如果我们帮他拜托了困境
But we get him out of this
如果他以后发现我的事
and he ever does find out about me,
他会欠我们一个人情
he's gonna owe us.
迈克  那个人绝不会因为我们帮他脱困
Mike, that man is never gonna compromise his ethics
就做些道德上的妥协
just because we got him out of a jam.
绝不会做道德上的妥协
Never gonna compromise his ethics?
你刚说他接受了贿赂
You just said he took a bribe.
那又有什么关系
So what does that have to do with anything?
这其中的关系很大
It has everything to do with everything
因为你不觉得他受贿了
because you don't think he did it.
-那又怎样  -又怎样
- So what? - So what?
那说明你拒绝他根本不是因为
That means you're not turning him down
你认为他是个见不得光的小人
because you think he's shady.
你
You're...
你拒绝他是因为
You're turning him down because you have
你对亨利·吉拉德还有怨气
a Henry Gerard-sized chip on your shoulder.
我没有怨气
I do not have a chip on my shoulder.
听起来像有
You sure sound like you do,
这把你变得比傻瓜还糟
which makes you worse than an idiot.
你就是个蠢货
It makes you a jackass.
-你说什么  -你听到了
- Excuse me? - You heard me.
你知道他把赔偿金分配得很公平
You know that he divided that money fairly,
这意味着你只是
which means that you're just--
我不在乎这意味着什么
I don't care what it means,
我也不需要你的说教
and I don't need a lecture from you.
显然你很需要
Apparently you do,
因为你差点就要为了
because you're about to screw over
跟某个伤害过你感情的人较劲
a bunch of innocent people
而危害很多无辜人的生活
just to stick it to some guy who hurt your feelings.
我从来没想过会对你
That's not something I ever thought
说出这种话
I'd be saying to you.
看看这是谁啊
Look who it is,
那个让打压我至此的女人
the woman who put me in my place.
又怎么了
What now?
你想让我再签个什么文件
You want me to sign a piece of paper
承认我就是那个草丘上的守望者吗
admitting that I was the man on the grassy knoll?
庆典上的话我都是发自肺腑的  路易
I meant what I said at the ceremony, Louis.
你是说那个为了引我签字
You mean the ceremony that you only had
才搞的庆典吗
in order to trick me?
我举办庆典是因为你要求了
I had it because you demanded it,
但我来不是谈那事的
but I'm not here to talk about that.
我来是想谈谈杰夫·马龙
I'm here to talk about Jeff Malone.
他怎么了
What about him?
你也许发现了他和我
You may be aware that he and I are--
五十度灰吗  我明白了
Fifty Shades of Grey? I'm aware.
这话我不跟你计较
I'm gonna let that go
因为你也许不知道
because you may also not be aware
我必须要对他撒谎
that I had to lie to him.
他不知道迈克的事  对吧
He doesn't know about Mike, does he?
不知道
No.
但他知道你犯了罪
But he does know you committed a crime
然后辞了职
and that you resigned
但现在你的名字高高的挂在了墙上
and now your name is up on the wall.
你怎么跟他说的
What'd you tell him?
我告诉他你发现了
I told him you found out
我隐瞒了丹尼尔·哈德曼挪用公款的事
that I covered up Daniel Hardman's embezzlement
然后用这件事要挟我
and that you used it to strong-arm me.
然后你现在想让我保守你的另一个秘密
And now you want me to protect another one of your secrets.
是同一个的秘密  路易
It's the same secret, Louis,
而且你在其中牵扯深度跟我一样
and you have just as much invested in it as I do.
不  不一样  因为我不在乎
No, I don't, because I don't care
你和杰夫的关系能不能维持下去
if your relationship with Jeff survives or not.
你想怎么样  路易
What do you want, Louis?
我想要长期帮你保守秘密的好处
I want something for continuing to cover your ass.
你已经得了好处  你的名字挂在墙上了
You got something. You got your name on the wall.
现在我想要与之匹配的尊重
Now I want the respect that comes with it.
意思是
Meaning?
我想要哈维的一个客户
I want one of Harvey's clients.
哪一个
Which one?
那是我和哈维之间的事
That's between me and Harvey.
好吧
Okay.
我同意见面
I agreed to meet.
我希望你不只是要再强调一遍
I hope it's not just so you can tell me
我是一个多糟糕的人
more about what a horrible person I am.
我来是要告诉你我改变了主意
I came here to tell you that I changed my mind.
所以你自己也承认了我没有受贿
So you admitted to yourself that I didn't do this?
我承认了你来找我
I've admitted to myself that you came to me
是因为这个案子不能循规蹈矩
because this case needs rule-bending,
并且你马上就要告诉我这其中的原因
and you're gonna tell me why right now.
那笔钱
The money.
是的  那笔钱
Yes, the money.
如果你没有受贿
If you weren't bribed,
那你是从哪里得来的那两万五千块
where the hell did you get that $25,000 from?
你知道那是从哪里来的
You know where it came from.
和你去年用来勒索我的
It's the same thing you tried to
事情是一样的
use to blackmail me last year.
让我把事情理一理
Let me get this straight.
你这笔钱的来源
You have an explanation for the money
有一个完美的解释
that would get you out of this whole thing.
但我却不能用
But I can't use it.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去帮你摆脱麻烦
To get you out of this.
欢迎来到现实世界  教授
Welcome to the real world, Professor.
我需要你帮我收集有关加勒特·布雷迪的一切消息
I need you to find out everything you can on Garrett Brady.
没问题  谁是加勒特·布雷迪
Absolutely. Who's Garrett Brady?
吉拉德案子的另一方
The guy on the other side of Gerard's suit.
等等
Wait a second.
这是不是意味着你接了他的案子
Does this mean you took his case?
你知道这意味着我接了他的案子
You know that means I took his case,
我也不想听到任何沾沾自喜的言论了
and I don't want to hear any gloating.
沾沾自喜  没有  没有
Gloating? No, no, no, no, no.
我没有  我没有沾沾自喜
I'm not-- I'm not gloating.
我只是意识到
I'm merely recognizing the fact that
你彻底改变主意
you completely changed your mind
完全是因为我的劝说
based entirely on what I said.
-这就是沾沾自喜  -算一个意思吧
- Which is gloating. - "Po-tay-to," "Po-tah-to."
但鉴于你还是会照自己方式想问题
But as long as you're gonna think of it that way,
所以我还要指出
I might as well point out
因为你听取了我的教诲
that since you listened to my lecture,
所以也许你该称我为  教授
maybe you should start calling me Professor.
如果你想不出吉拉德不在场证明之外的办法
I'm gonna start calling you unemployed
我就要称你为失业者了
if you don't figure out a way around using Gerard's alibi.
等等  我们不能说出钱的来源吗
Wait, we can't say where the money came from?
不能  因为他是玩地下扑克赢来的
No, we can't, because he was playing backroom poker,
如果被发现  哈佛会炒了他
and if that comes out, Harvard fires him.
不是开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
他是伦理学教授  却破坏法律
He's an ethics professor, and he's breaking the law?
你以为我威慑么讨厌他
Where the hell do you think my chip comes from?
如果我们不能用本有的辩护
Well, if we can't use his alibi,
又怎么帮他摆脱官司呢
how are we supposed to get him out of this?
我不知道  教授
I don't know, Professor,
但是  是你要我们接手这个案子的
but you're the one who wanted us to take this case,
所以为什么不好好利用你硕大的头脑
so why don't you use that big brain of yours
想出解决办法呢
and find a solution?
把亨利·吉拉德的案子给我
You're giving me Henry Gerard.
什么
What?
我看到他了  我要他
I saw him. I want him.
你接了他的委托  把他给我
You got him. He's mine.
这样做可行不通  路易
That's not the way it works, Louis.
你恐怕得另找一个男朋友
I'm afraid you'll have to find yourself another boyfriend.
这样做必须行得通
Oh, this is exactly how it works.
你去跟杰西卡谈过了  是不是
You talked to Jessica, didn't you?
当然  她利用我给自己擦屁股
Sure did, and she used me to cover her ass,
所以我要你的一个客户作为回报
so I get one of your clients in return.
你要我的一个客户  这个可以谈
You want one of my clients, we can talk about that,
但是吉拉德不能给你
but Gerard's staying with me.
得了  别装得好像
Please, don't pretend
自己真心在乎他
like you actually care about him.
他甚至都忍不了你
He can't even stand you.
路易  我已经说了要考虑给你
Louis, I just offered to consider giving you
我的一位客户
one of my clients,
你就放过吉拉德吧
so I suggest you let Gerard go.
不  我不放过任何人
No, I'm not letting anything go,
因为没道理那么做
because it doesn't make any sense.
他不但忍不了你
Not only can't he stand you.
还很不尊敬你  因为他...
He doesn't respect you because he's got things...
你刚才说什么
What did you just say to me?
我说他并不尊敬你
I said he doesn't respect you.
你猜怎么的
Well, you know what?
他也绝对不会尊敬你
He definitely doesn't respect you,
因为他跟我说  他需要律师的时候
because when he told me he needed a lawyer,
我试图把他推给你
I tried to send him your way,
而他说
and his exact words were,
"我不要路易  我要你"
"I don't want Louis. I want you."
很好
Fine.
那就给我另一个客户吧
Then I'll just take another one of your clients.
-你什么也得不到  -你刚刚说...
- You're not taking a thing. - You just said that I could...
我不在乎刚才说过什么
Look, I don't give a shit what I just said, okay?
我的客户就是我的客户
My clients are my clients.
如果你不在三秒钟内
And you don't get out of my office
离开我的办公室
in the next three seconds,
你我之间一定有事发生
something's gonna happen between you and me,
而且我保证  此事一旦发生
and I guarantee it won't end with you
你的牙肯定保不全
keeping all of your teeth.
不
No.
回去  别进来
Just turn around and walk right back out that door.
-哈维  -你听到我说的了吗
- Harvey. - Did you hear what I said?
听到了  但显然你没听到
I did, but apparently, you didn't hear
杰西卡所说的息事宁人
what Jessica said about wiping the slate clean.
显然  你也没听到我说了什么
And apparently, you didn't hear what I said,
因为我刚才跟路易说  可以给他一位客户
because I just told Louis he could have one of my clients.
三秒之后你又跟他说不行
And three seconds later, you told him he couldn't.
因为我意识到
because I realized that
我是在为杰西卡的错误买单
I'm paying for Jessica's mistake.
不  哈维  你本愿意为她买单的
No, Harvey, you were willing to pay for her mistake
直到路易说吉拉德不尊敬你
right up until Louis said Gerard doesn't respect you.
跟那个没关系
Oh, that has nothing to do with it.
你可以自欺欺人
You can lie to yourself all you want,
但我才不会让你糊弄我
but I'm not gonna let you bullshit me.
你在说什么鬼话
What the hell are you talking about?
亨利·吉拉德是你尊敬的人之一
Henry Gerard is the one person you respect
而他却不尊敬你  路易碰到了你这根敏感神经
who never respected you, and Louis touched that nerve.
我说了  跟那个没关系
And I told you that has nothing to do with it.
你真心这么想吗
You really think that?
不是这么想  就是这么回事
I don't think it. I know it.
这么说来  哈维
Then you know what, Harvey?
你跟路易没区别
You're no different than Louis,
因为你本来有机会帮我们渡过难关
because you have a chance to help us all move on,
却因为一点小事毁了一切
and you are blowing it off out of pettiness,
路易就是这种人
which is exactly what Louis would do.
你要我怎么做  唐娜
What do you want from me, Donna?
我要你成熟点
I want you to be a grown-up
做你承诺要做的事
and do what you said you'd do in the first place.
有进展吗
You got something?
有  我们忽略了最明显的事
Yeah, we've been overlooking the obvious.
别让我一个接一个问问题
Yeah, I'm not in the mood for 20 questions.
赶紧直说
Give it to me.
除非你在不上报的情况下出国
Unless you're traveling internationally and don't report it,
否则带现金上飞机
carrying cash on board a plane
不算犯罪
isn't a crime.
很好  但事实是
Great, except for the fact
吉拉德没有被指控走私
that Gerard's not being charged with smuggling.
而是被起诉了受贿
He's being sued.
没错  但我想说的是
Right, but my point is,
加勒特·布雷迪是怎么发现的呢
how did Garrett Brady even find that out?
他发现了  是因为吉拉德
Well, he found out because Gerard
被运输安全管理局扣住了
was detained by the TSA.
运安局只跟他谈了五分钟
Who talked to him for five minutes
然后就放他走了
and then sent him on his way.
这种调查根本不会被记录在案
Those searches aren't a matter of public record.
-没错  -该死
- Exactly. - Holy shit.
布雷迪贿赂了运安局
Brady bribed the T.S.A..
这不仅违法
Which isn't only illegal.
而且能让那份报告被驳回
It makes that report totally inadmissible.
是你自己想出的这个办法吗
You figured this out on your own?
我本可以更快搞定的
Well, I would've done it faster,
可是我实在想先点份寿司吃
but I had to order some sushi.
"本可以更快搞定"
"Would've done it faster."
你第一周来上班就是这么说的
That's what you said your first week here,
只不过那时吃的是匹萨  不是寿司
except it was pizza instead of sushi.
是的  我成长了
Yeah, I'm growing.
你想说瑞秋教会了你什么叫吃东西吧
You mean Rachel taught you how to eat.
我说了  我成长了
Like I said, I'm growing.
唐娜  我现在很忙
Hey, Donna, I'm a little busy at the moment.
忙得顾不上接这个吗
Too busy to take on this?
那是什么
What's that?
只不过是哈维当上冠名合伙人以后
Just the first client that Jessica gave Harvey
杰西卡给他的第一个委托人
when he made name partner.
哈维说他不会给我任何委托人的
Harvey said he wouldn't let me have any of his clients.
不  他说会给你
No. He said he would.
可随后你不仅不接受
But then instead of taking him up on it,
还伤了他的感情
you went ahead and shit on his feelings.
拜托  哈维根本没有感情
Please. Harvey doesn't have feelings.
这不是真的  你很清楚
That's not true, and you know it.
而且你应该最清楚人在伤心的时候
And you of all people should know that a person
会反应过度
can overreact when they're hurt.
如果你在含沙射影地说我
If you're referring to me,
我可没有反应过度...
I do not overreact when--
出自《瘦虎肥龙》
随便你  胖子神探
Okay, whatever you say, Fatty-Baldy.
够了  从我办公室滚出去...
Okay, get the hell out of my office and--
好吧  你说得稍微有那么一点小道理
Fine, you have a small, legitimate point.
我真的伤到他的感情了吗
I really hurt his feelings?
是的  千真万确
Yeah, you really did.
但然后他意识到他反应过度了
But then he realized he was overreacting
他意识到这是一个能让我们大家
and that this was a chance for us all
重归旧好的机会
to get back to where we were.
你能发誓那是他当上冠名合伙人之后
You swear that is the first client
杰西卡给他的第一个委托人吗
that Jessica gave him after me made name partner?
我发誓
I swear.
把档案给我吧
Leave me the file.
你们两个先点吧  我还没想好
You two go ahead. I haven't decided yet.
一种用鹰嘴豆泥捏成团炸熟的小吃
实际上我们不是来吃法拉费的
Actually, we're not here for the falafel.
我们来向你自我介绍
We're here to introduce ourselves.
取餐处
迈克·罗斯
Mike Ross.
哈维·斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
我们代理了亨利·吉拉德
We represent Henry Gerard.
这样的话那还是让我请你们吃午饭吧
Well, in that case, let me buy you two lunch,
因为我马上要赢一场出乎意料的大官司了
because I'm about to come into an unexpected windfall.
看来你经常这样啊
Well, I guess that's your thing--
付钱让人办事
paying people off.
我希望你贿赂运管局用的不是劣质法拉费
I hope the TSA got more than some shitty falafel.
你们到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我在说这个
I'm talking about this.
行贿
Bribery?
多讽刺啊  不是吗
Ironic, isn't it?
你因为受贿而起诉吉拉德教授
You suing Professor Gerard for accepting a bribe
结果你才是向联邦雇员行贿的那个人
when you're the one paying off federal employees.
只是被指控行贿  律师
Allegedly paying, Counselor.
小心起诉你们诽谤哦
You don't want to slander me.
-所以你承认了  -我什么都没承认
- So you admit it. - I don't admit a thing.
你们的委托人从火车出轨受害人身上牟利
Your client sold out victims of a train derailment.
他必须付出代价
He's going to pay.
你现在可能不愿意承认任何事
You may not be willing to admit anything here,
但到了法官面前你就得承认了
but you'll have to in front of the judge.
因为我准备申请传唤
Because I've drafted subpoenas
那晚当班的所有运管局雇员
for every TSA employee on duty that night.
撤诉吧  布雷迪先生
Drop the case, Mr. Brady.
你们这是在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
不  我们只是告知你
No, we're informing you.
那让我来告知你们
Well, let me inform you.
希望你们没忘记  运管局
In case you forgot, the TSA falls
归属国土安全部管辖
under the Department of Homeland Security,
因此这属于国家安全问题
which makes this a national security issue.
这跟国家安全一毛钱关系都没有
This has nothing to do with national security,
你心知肚明
and you know it.
我只知道政府在一位乘客身上
All I know is the government found
发现了大量现金
a large sum of cash on a passenger.
至于他们是怎么知道的
Now, how they came to know that,
他们接下来怎么调查的
how they proceeded to investigate that,
或者他们拿这一消息怎么办
or what they did with that information
都是政府的事
is the government's business.
你就打算拿这个当挡箭牌吗
And that's what you're going with?
不是我打算拿这个当挡箭牌
That's not what I'm going with.
而是他们会拿这个当挡箭牌
That's what they're going to go with.
所以随便你们传唤多少运管局探员
So you can call up as many TSA agents as you like,
他们一个字都不会说的
but they're not gonna be saying a thing.
你们还是自己买法拉费吧
And you can buy your own damn falafel.
我需要魅力派美妆的资料
I need Cutie Pie Cosmetics.
你又想来找茬吗
You want to try that again?
我今晚要和琼·沃尔什见面
I have a meeting with Joan Walsh tonight,
我需要她的档案
and I need her files.
琼是哈维的委托人
Joan is Harvey's client.
-不再是了  -从什么时候开始
- Not anymore. - Since when?
从什么时候开始不重要
Since it doesn't matter,
我可是冠名合伙人
because I'm name partner,
这意思是我说我需要什么
which means when I say I need something,
你的回答应该是
your response should either be,
"要多少"或者"还需要别的吗"
"How high?" or "Can I have another?"
好吧
Fine.
你需要知道几件事...
There are a few things that you should know--
我需要知道就是
You see, what I know is
你老板以为
your boss seems to think
只要让唐娜安排一顿上等的晚餐
all it takes to impress Joan Walsh
就能打动琼·沃尔什
is getting Donna to make a fancy dinner reservation,
而我却会用我超凡的法律能力打动她
but I'm going to impress her with so much legal domination
今夜过去
that by the end of the night,
她压根不会记得
all she's gonna be able to say is,
哈维·斯佩克特是老几
"Harvey Specter who?"
-好  这就是一个错误...  -错误吗
- Okay, that's a mistake-- - A mistake?
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
你是想用你的法律能力
You're trying to impress me
来打动我
with your legal domination
证明你不是小小的律师助理
to prove that you're not just a paralegal
而是名合格的律师
but an associate.
不是的  路易  我...
No, Louis. I'm--
听着  我根本不关心你怎么看自己
See, I don't care what you call yourself.
所以除非你糟糕到
So unless you did such a shitty job,
把那份档案写得狗屁不通
the files are unreadable,
否则就赶紧交给我
hand 'em over to me right now.
这样才像话
That's more like it.
这是什么
What's this?
我知道你今晚需要工作
I know you have to work tonight,
但你也需要吃东西
but you also need to eat.
这可不只是吃东西
I wouldn't call this just eating.
一次性盘子可配不上你
Well, you deserve better than paper plates.
我不介意一次性盘子啊
I don't mind paper plates.
我知道你不介意
Oh, I know you don't.
我只是说它配不上你
I just said you deserve better.
这是炖牛肉吗
Is that Ropa Vieja?
我亲手做的
I made it myself.
也就是说你是从四十街和莱克斯街交叉口
Which means you got it at the Cuban place
那家我最喜欢的古巴餐厅买来的
that I love on 40th and Lex.
亲手买来
By myself.
我干了什么获此殊荣
What did I do to deserve this?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是...
I'm just...
觉得咱俩关系进了一步
feeling closer.
因为我信赖你
Because I confided in you.
因为你的心防正在坍塌
Because the walls are coming down,
我感觉得到
and I can feel it.
我何德何能拥有你
What did I do to deserve you?
我们可以边吃这顿
Well, we can talk about that
全部由我烹制的晚餐  边谈这件事
over this delicious meal that I made all by myself.
敬我们
To us.
然后我说  "海伦
And then I said, "Helen,
那不是纯种博美犬
that's no Pomeranian.
而是混血博美
That's a Pomimo.
你上当啦"
You've been had."
太搞笑了
That is hilarious.
真的  狗狗啊  它们...
Really, dogs, they are--
它们真是太迷人了
they are so fascinating.
你养了很多狗吗  路易
Do you have many dogs, Louis?
才没有
Hell, no.
因为楼规不让养  真是群混...
Building regulations-- it's a cluster of f-f-f...
我和他们斗争好多年了
I've been fighting them for years.
-太可怕了  -是啊
- Oh, that's horrible. - Yes.
你的股权现在也不容乐观啊
As is what's going on with your stock.
路易  我们在吃晚饭呢
Louis, we're having dinner.
-把那玩意拿开  -不不不
- Put that away. - No, no, no.
我只是想着你可能会有兴趣知道
But I just thought you'd be interested to know that
我们可以让股价飙升
we could skyrocket the share price--
现在  我的兴趣只在
Right now what I'm interested in
再点一杯曼哈顿鸡尾酒
is having another Manhattan
以及听听甜品单上有什么
and hearing what's on the dessert list.
你不需要看单子  点法国焦糖蛋奶冻就好
You don't need a list. Get the Crème brulée.
现在  这个股权问题  我有...
Now, this stock issue, I have--
把文件传真到我办公室
Fax the papers to my office,
然后等我回家了再看
and I'll review them when I get home.
等回家再看
When you get home?
搞什么...
What the f-f...
那我们到底是为什么出来用晚餐
What the hell did we come to dinner for, then?
为了这个啊
For this.
"这个"指什么
What this?
这个
This.
好吧
Okay.
我不知道哈维是如何处理这些季度报告的
I don't know how Harvey handled these quarterly reviews,
-但是我...  -哈维...
- but I-- - Oh, Harvey...
他真是太棒了
was magnificent.
老实说  当我听说将由你来代替他
Truth be told, I was a little disappointed
处理这件事时
when I heard that you'd be handling this
我有点失望
instead of him,
但我还没看过你跳恰恰舞呢
but I haven't seen your cha-cha yet,
所以尚未有定论
so the jury's still out.
Jury有陪审团之意
此句直译为"陪审团还没回来"
这是个律师笑话
That was a lawyer joke.
是的  我听明白了
Yep. Got it.
没错
Yep.
听着  琼
Listen, Joan,
我觉得你真的会很高兴
I think you're gonna be really glad
今晚在这里的是我
that it was me here tonight,
因为我已经送了封信给你的董事会了
because I already sent a letter to your board.
-然后我...  -你干了什么
- And I--  - You did what?
我通知了他们这件事
I notified them of this.
那就是...
That's --
我一直试图告诉你的事
what I'm trying to tell you.
你为什么要做这种显而易见的蠢事
Why the hell would you do something so patently stupid?
蠢
Stupid?
我可不是靠卖蠢当上冠名合伙人的
Hey, I didn't become name partner being stupid.
不是吗
Didn't you?
董事会中的两名成员
Two members of my board
马上就要到任期年限了
are about to reach their term limits.
其中至少有一人已被魅力美妆公司选定了
At least one is being circled by Glamour Cosmetics.
你刚刚把一个我研发了数年的产品
You have just notified that person of a product
告诉了那个人
that I've had in R & D for years,
如今他们能拿这个到我最大的竞争对手那
and now they can trade information for a seat
里去换取董事会席位了
on the board of my biggest competitor.
琼  我不知道...
Joan, I didn't know--
告诉我  利特先生
Tell me, Mr. Litt,
你真的是从法学院毕业的吗
did you actually graduate from law school,
还是花钱买的文凭
or did you just buy your way onto the letterhead?
你最好把包放下
Yeah, you better put that bag down,
因为我们整晚都要待在这里了
because we're staying all night.
琼的事情进行的不顺利  是吧
Didn't go well with Joan, did it?
是不顺利  因为你拖了我后腿
No, it didn't, because you sandbagged me.
我没有拖你后腿
I didn't sandbag you.
那你怎么称呼"没告诉我
Well, then what do you call not telling me
魅力美妆在挖她董事会成员"这件事
that Glamour was circling her board members?
我试着告诉你来着
I tried to tell you,
但是你在狂怒之下什么也听不进去
but you couldn't hear me through all of your rage.
我现在没听见的
What I'm not hearing
是你把包包放下的声音
is the sound of you putting your bag down,
因为明天下午董事会成员就要开会了
because the board members are meeting tomorrow afternoon,
而我必须在那之前补救这件事
and I only have until then to fix this.
你是想要我帮你吗
And you want me to help you?
你是这个案子的律师  不是吗
You're the associate on this case, aren't you?
-现在我又成律师了  -你猜怎么着
- So now I'm an associate? - Hey, you know what?
现在不是讨论这个的好时候
Now is not the time to get into it.
不  现在恰恰是讨论这个的好时候
No, now is exactly the time to get into it,
因为你抓住每一个机会
because you have taken every opportunity possible
让我觉得自己一无是处
to make me feel like I am nothing,
而如今  就算你有求于我
and now, even though you want something,
你还是不把我当回事
you're still treating me like I'm nothing.
我对你和对其他每一个律师没什么不同
I'm treating you like every other associate.
那是胡话  你猜怎么着
That is bullshit, and you know what?
就算真是这样
Even if it were true,
你以前不是这样对我的
you didn't used to treat me that way.
那是因为我以前不知道你每天都在欺骗我
I didn't used to know you lied to me on a daily basis.
路易  假如我拿上包走人
Louis, it would serve you right
回家到我爱的人身边  留你一人在这里
if I take my bag and leave you here
也是你活该
and go home to the man that I love.
所以你是不打算帮忙了
So you're not gonna help.
不  我会帮你的
No, I'm gonna help you,
但不是因为你理应得到我的帮助
but not because you deserve it.
我会帮你  是因为我是一名律师
I'll do it because I am an associate,
而且我是专业的
and I am a professional,
这意味着为了做好我的工作
which means I am capable
我能够将私人情感放在一边
of putting the personal aside in order to do my job.
麻烦再要一个那个
And one of those, please.
我正好想要来一个
Just what I was in the mood for.
你要买百吉饼
Ah, you're getting a bagel.
那就是说你成功了
That means you kicked ass.
的确如此
Which I did.
你是打了电话给运管局
You called up the TSA,
攻破了他们国家安全级别的防线吗
busted up their national security defense?
不  我利用了他们的防线
No, I used their defense.
吉拉德会在保密的情况下作证
Gerard's gonna testify under seal
因为这事关国家安全
because it's a matter of national security.
法官会信吗
And the Judge bought that?
当然会信了
What's not to buy?
运管局为我们铺好了路
The TSA made the argument for us.
布雷迪怎么说
And what did Brady say?
这是最精彩的部分
That's the best part about it.
他完全不知情
He doesn't even know it.
因为事关国家安全
It's a matter of national security.
我们在保密情况下作证
We testify under seal,
法官意识到吉拉德是个堕落的赌徒
the Judge realizes that Gerard is a degenerate gambler...
但也是个公正的调解员
But a fair mediator.
这个案子被驳回  加勒特·布雷迪
The case gets dismissed, and Garrett Brady
和哈佛法学院根本不会知道这件事
and Harvard Law never know it happened.
这都是你想出来的
You thought of all of that on your own?
你以为只有你能想出一个
You think you're the only one who can come up
聪明的解决办法吗
with an intelligent solution?
我们共事这么久
You are 1 for 400
四百个案子里你也就能想出一个
in the time we've worked together.
好了  聪明人  既然我替你干了你的活
Okay, smart guy, since I did your job for you,
你就得帮我做我的
you're gonna do my job for me.
你想让我帮吉拉德做取证预演
You want me to prep Gerard
因为你不想跟他共处一室
because you don't want to sit in a room
听他唠叨两个小时
and listen to him talk for two hours.
十五年前我就我不想
I didn't want to 15 years ago,
现在更不想
and I don't want to now.
我们只有一次机会
We only get one shot at this,
他的证词一定要无懈可击
and his testimony better be rock solid.
谢了
Thanks.
拿走吧  别客气
Oh, yeah, sure, help yourself!
混蛋
Dick.
你一宿没睡啊
I see you haven't slept.
我要处理的事太多了
I have a lot of work that needs attending to.
我猜也是  鉴于今天早上
I bet you do, considering the phone call
我接到了琼·沃尔什的电话
I got from Joan Walsh this morning.
她给你打电话了
She called you?
她想知道某位冠名合伙人浑水摸鱼的事
She wanted to know what the other name partners
另一位冠名合伙人要怎么处理
were going to do about the one that screwed the pooch.
得了吧  这不公平
Oh, come on, that is not fair.
我没拿到所有的信息...
I didn't have all the information--
你倒是有足够的信息
You had enough information
跟她谈条件  把她从哈维手里抢过来
to make a deal to get her from Harvey,
条件当中还包括瞒着我和杰夫
and part of that deal was you backing me with Jeff.
你是因为这个才来的
Oh, so that's why you're here.
你不相信我能搞定
You don't trust I'm still gonna do it?
因为你到现在都没搞定
Because you haven't done it yet,
而且你不止一次在事情不按设想发展时
and you have a history of making poor decisions
做出错误决定了
when things aren't going your way.
我唯一的错误决定
The only poor decision I've made
就是同意帮你隐瞒真相
is agreeing to cover for you in the first place.
你用这件事当把柄为自己谋利的时候
You didn't think that was such a bad idea
也没觉得有什么不好啊
when you were using it to get what you wanted.
现在你在威胁要夺走我的成果吗
And now you're threatening to take that thing away.
路易  你想留住琼
Louis, you want to keep Joan,
那是你的事
that's on you,
但我好好履行了我们的交易
but I held up my end of the bargain.
你最好别玩砸了
You better hold up yours.
我只是想在回顾一遍  教授
I just want to go over it one more time, Professor.
赌注有多少钱
How much money was in that pot?
我已经回顾烦了
I'm tried of going over it.
为什么我们非得一遍又一遍地
Why do we have to keep replaying
从头回想呢
every moment of this game?
因为它是整个案子的关键
Because your entire case depends on it.
我的案子取决于那些钱是我赌博赢的
My case depends on the fact that I won that money gambling,
我是不是用同花赢得很重要吗
not whether I won it with a flush.
案子想获胜的关键是法官相信你的话
Your case depends on the judge believing you,
如果他在你的证词里找出任何漏洞  那我们
and if he finds any holes in your testimony, then we--
我把赌桌上所有人的名字告诉你
I gave you the names of everyone I knew at that game.
但你赢得那些钱的时候他们都不在
But none of those men were there when you won that money.
我不知道手下败将的名字  我也没办法
I can't help it if I didn't get the name of the guy I beat.
所以你的故事必须无懈可击
Which is why your story needs to be rock solid.
好吧
Okay.
继续吧
Go ahead.
所以我再问你一遍  教授
So I ask you again, Professor,
最终局的赌注有多少钱
how much money was in the final pot?
大约一万二
Roughly $12,000.
然后你赢了
And you won that hand.
就像我说过的  我赢了
As I said before, I won,
然后我将筹码兑现
and then I cashed out.
你的牌是什么来着
And what did you have again?
Q同花
A queen-high flush.
输家是谁
And who did you beat?
我说过了  我不知道他的名字
I told you, I didn't get his name.
那他的牌是什么
Okay, so what did he have?
Q和6的双对
Two pair, queens over sixes.
等一下
Wait a second.
你之前说你旁边的人
You said before that the man next to you
手里有两个Q
folded with two queens up,
现在这人手里又有两个Q
and now this guy has two queens,
你还是个Q同花
and you had a queen-high flush?
我之前说我旁边的人
I said that the man next to me
手里是两张K
folded with two kings.
不  你不是这么说的
No, you didn't.
你听错了
You heard me wrong.
我没听错
No, I didn't.
这到底是在取证预演
Is this part of prepping me,
还是你在指控我
or are you accusing me of something?
我在帮你把故事捋顺
I'm trying to get your story to line up.
-我的故事没问题  -我觉得有问题
- My story does line up. - Not to me, it doesn't.
年轻人  如果你坐在这
Look, young man, if you're gonna sit over there
说我是骗子
and call me a liar--
我没说你是骗子
I'm not calling you a liar,
但如果你明天照今天这么说
but if you say tomorrow what you said today,
我们的麻烦就大了
we're gonna be in a lot of trouble,
因为据我所知
because where I come from,
一副扑克只有四张Q
there are only four queens in a deck.
我说的是两张K
I said two kings,
我明天也会这么说
and I'm gonna say that again tomorrow.
做好你的工作
So you do your job,
我也会做好我的
and I'm gonna do mine.
他在撒谎
He's lying.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
吉拉德那个打扑克赢钱的故事
Gerard's story about winning all that money
纯属一派胡言
playing poker is bullshit.
好吧  慢点说  到底发生了什么
All right, slow down. What the hell happened?
我算过了  玩家手里的牌对不上
I did the math, and the hands don't add up.
什么叫你算过了
What do you mean you did the math?
他先是说第四张牌抓到的是Q
I mean first he said that he drew a queen on fourth street,
之后我跟他确认的时候...
and then when I pressed him about it, he--
等一下
Wait a second.
你这结论是根据他在盘问时
This conclusion is based on him recalling hands
他回忆的牌得出的
under cross-examination?
哈维  我在大西洋城
Harvey, I got kicked out
因为算牌被赶出去过
of Atlantic City for counting cards.
我了解这种把戏
I know this shit.
那也不能说明他撒谎了
It doesn't mean he's lying.
我对这种情况也有点经验
I got a little experience with that too,
我告诉你  他撒谎了
and I'm telling you, he was.
-或许他只是累了  -或者我猜对了
- Or maybe he's tired. - Or maybe I'm right.
或者你根本不知道你在说什么
Or maybe you don't know what the hell you're talking about.
为什么你总是为他辩护
Why are you defending him?
是你叫我辩护的
Because you asked me to.
哈维
Look, Harvey,
我没说他受贿了
I'm not saying that he took a bribe.
我只想说他那笔钱不是玩牌得来的
I'm just saying that he didn't get that money playing poker.
除非他承认了  否则明天还得出庭作证
Well, unless he admitted that, he's testifying tomorrow.
你从什么时候开始成了鸵鸟
Since when do you stick your head in the sand?
-他承认了吗  -没有
- Did he admit it? - No, he didn't.
但他什么细节都对不上  这不应该
But he screwed up the details, and he shouldn't have,
如果说的是真话  可不会这样
because people who are telling the truth get it right.
你心里也清楚
And you know it.
那是什么
What's that?
对J三张四  满堂彩
Jacks full of fours.
我知道  但为什么...
I can see that, but why--
为什么把它们摆在你面前吗
Why is it staring you in the face?
我上回就靠这一手赚了一大笔
It's what I threw down the last time I won a huge hand.
那是六个礼拜前  我还能记得
It was six weeks ago, and I can remember every hand
那张桌上每一个玩家的每一手牌
that every player at that table had.
如果你那天晚上赢钱了
Now, if you won money the other night,
你也会记得的
you'd remember it too.
我记得啊
I do remember,
就像我跟你的律师说的...
and as I explained to your associate--
够了  别糊弄我了
Yeah, stop bullshitting me.
那笔钱究竟是从哪里来的
Where the hell did that money really come from?
如果你不说真话
'Cause if you don't tell me the truth,
我就取消明天的听证会
I'm canceling that hearing right now.
钱是从...
It came...
我一个学生那儿来的
from a student of mine.
做什么用
For what?
让我帮他改成绩
In exchange for changing his grade.
我的天  要两万五
Jesus Christ. For $25,000?
他本会挂了我这门课
He was going to fail my class,
这会影响一些公司录取他...
and that would've stopped him from getting an offer from--
你这个伪君子
You goddamn hypocrite.
你满嘴道德伦理却做出这种事
You preach about ethics, and you do this?
这是道德伦理的事
This is about ethics.
你根本不知道我为何如此
And you don't have any idea why I did it.
我才不在意你的动机
I don't care why you did it.
我只关心你让我做了什么
I care about what you're making me do,
我是不会去做伪证的
because I am not suborning perjury.
你敢说没做过比这更过分的事吗
Well, you tell me that you've never done anything worse.
我就知道
I knew it.
如果是其他人你就帮了这个忙
You would do it for someone else...
但就是不会帮我
but not for me.
你知道吗  教授
You know what, Professor?
其实我内心还是有一点点指望
There's a small part of me that actually thought
你觉得我是最好的律师才来找我
that you came to me because you thought I'm the best,
但你竟然以为我会为了赢不择手段
but you just think I'll do whatever it takes to win.
不就是这样你才是最厉害的律师吗
Isn't that what makes you the best?
找其他人替你做这些卑鄙勾当
Get someone else to do your dirty work,
我是不会替你做伪证的
because I'm not suborning perjury.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
促进我的血液流通
Getting my blood flowing.
我在这里坐了一晚
I've been sitting here all night,
每小时有14个人死于下肢不宁综合症
and restless leg syndrome kills 14 people every hour.
我觉得这数字不太准确
I don't think that's accurate.
我不管你怎么觉得  有进展吗
I don't care what you think. What do you have?
我找到能够挽回琼的方法了
I found a way to fix things with Joan.
好吧  你想说研发部门的东西
Okay, you're arguing anything in R & D
是自主知识产权
is the intellectual property
产权属于产品的提出者
of the person who suggested the product?
直到研发结果公布于众
Until such time that the results become public.
我向董事会递信那一刻就公开了
Which they did the second I sent the board that letter.
但董事会成员受
Except board members are subject
保密协定约束
to the nondisclosure agreement.
他们并没有签署
Well, the board members haven't signed
保密协定啊
a nondisclosure agreement.
是还没
Yet.
万一他们不愿意签怎么办
What's to stop them from refusing?
不怎么办  如果他们不签字
Nothing, but if they do,
非竞争条款就派上用场了
then the noncompete kicks in.
以诉讼为威胁
Preventing them from revealing the contents of my letter
防止公布那封信的内容
under threat of prosecution.
特别是针对商业间谍诉讼
Specifically corporate espionage.
我的天  你这个点子是从...
Oh, my God. You got this idea from--
-我们的章程里来的  -我写的章程
- Our bylaws. - My bylaws.
瑞秋  我的天  这真是...
Rachel, holy shit, this is...
可以接受的方法
acceptable.
我觉得你想说的那个词是"了不起"
I think the word you're looking for is "Awesome."
我想说的是"出去
Well, the word I'm saying is, "Get out,
因为我有个会要准备"
because I have a meeting to prepare for."
你知道吗  路易  我为此工作了整晚
You know what, Louis? I have been working all night.
这解救你于水火
And this gets your ass out of a major sling,
所以与其赶我走
so instead of dismissing me,
你该让我跟你一起去
you should be asking me to come with you.
抱歉  专业小姐
Excuse me, Miss Professional.
你不是希望我对律师一视同仁吗
You wanted me to treat you like every other associate.
-现在就是  -像我什么都没做一样对我
- Now I am. - By acting as if I did nothing?
不  认可你做的工作就是一视同仁
No, by acknowledging you did acceptable work.
让你和我一起去这种事
Letting you come with me is something
是我把你当朋友才可能发生的
that I would only do for you if we were friends,
但我们不是朋友
which we are not.
你取消了听证会
You canceled the hearing.
你说得对
You were right.
他撒谎了
He was lying.
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
在我发现赌博的真相后
You know, I knew he was a hypocrite
已经知道他是个伪君子
after I found out about the gambling.
可我从来没想过他会出卖哈佛
I never thought he'd sell out Harvard.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
他确实受了贿
He did take the bribe,
但与意外的受害者无关
but it had nothing to do with the accident victims.
他受贿帮一个学生改成绩
He did it to change someone's grade.
他为什么要这么做
Why would he do that?
这动机还重要吗
What difference does it make?
无论如何  他都曾要我替他做伪证
Either way, he was gonna let me suborn perjury.
如果我们要赢这案子  动机当然重要
It makes a difference because we still have to win this case.
我才不在乎这个案子能不能赢
Oh, I don't give a shit about winning this case.
我从来没听你这么说过
I've never heard you say anything like that before.
每一个案子  每一场比赛
You--you care about winning every case,
每一次辩论你都想赢
every game, every argument.
你听见我说的了吗
Did you hear me?
他要让我去做伪证
He was gonna let me suborn perjury.
如果能就此逃过一劫
And so would every client you have
你所有客户都会要求你这么做啊
if they thought they'd get away with it.
他不是其他的客户
He's not every client.
他是你之前就很讨厌的人
No, he's the one you hated in the first place.
-我没有讨厌他  -哈维  到底怎么了
- I didn't hate him. - Harvey, what is going on here?
我以为和我们比  他是个好人
I thought he was better than us.
我坐在教室里听他讲课
I sat in that class and listened to him talk
讲我们以后应该成为什么样的律师
about what kind of lawyers we should be,
而我总是让他失望  因为我知道
and I always let him down because I knew
他说的那种律师赢不了官司
that wasn't the kind of lawyer that wins.
但是我想要胜利
And I wanted to win.
所以我跟他争论
So I'd argue with him,
所以他鄙视我
and he'd look down on me.
但现在不是你让他失望
And now instead of you letting him down,
是他让你失望了
he let you down.
最后证明他并没有比我们好到哪里去
He turned out to be no better than any of us.
那我们就把他变得比我们好
So then let's make him better than us.
魅力派
沃尔什小姐
Miss Walsh.
我今天没预约见你
You are not on my schedule today.
沃尔什小姐  请看下这个
Ah, ah, Miss Walsh, please take a look at this.
这是什么
What is it?
弥补错误的机会
It's a chance to make things right.
你不能因为董事会成员可以开报销单
You cannot call board members employees
就把他们当普通雇员
based on them having access to an expense account.
不只是报销单
Not just an expense account.
他们还有公司信用卡和常设办公室
They have corporate cards and standing offices,
这些都在国内税收法规的
which, as defined by section 14.2
第14.2栏里注明了的
of the Internal Revenue Code,
他们就是一般雇员
makes them employees.
利特先生
Well, Mr. Litt,
看来我不需要再指定其他律师了
seems I won't be demanding a new point person after all.
很高兴听您这么说
I'm glad to hear that.
真的吗
Are you?
当然
Of course I am.
你是我成为冠名合伙人后的第一位委托人
You're my first client as name partner.
您对我来说非常重要
You're very important to me.
再有人成为新冠名合伙人的时候
Well, I suppose we'll find out the truth
我再看你是不是真的这么想了
when someone else makes name partner.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我不傻
I'm not an idiot.
我知道我在你们律所是个烫手山芋
I know that no one in your firm wants to deal with me.
不是这样
That's not true.
事实上  你是我争取来的
In fact, I fought for you.
你可能以为你是费力争取的
You may have thought you were fighting for me,
但我知道我是杰西卡扔给哈维的
but I know that Jessica dumped me on Harvey,
看起来你一成为冠名合伙人
and it seems that the second you made name partner,
哈维就把我扔给了你
Harvey did the same thing to you.
哦  你不知道啊
Oh, you didn't know that, did you?
那看来我们是挺有缘的
Then maybe we were meant for each other,
因为我们都是被抛弃的那个
since we're both left out of the club.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
你高谈阔论地说要修复友谊
You make this big speech about repairing our friendship,
结果只是说说而已
and all it was  more words.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你说服了我去接下琼的单子
You convinced me to take Joan,
然后顺便隐瞒了你其实
while conveniently leaving out the fact
是在帮哈维的事实
you're doing Harvey a favor.
路易  那不是我劝你原因
That's not why I did it, Louis.
好  那你现在告诉我  哈维受得了琼吗
Well, just tell me right now, can he stand her?
受不了  但他是打算留着这个单子的
No, but he was gonna keep her
因为你...
because you--
伤害了他宝贵的感情  我知道
Hurt his precious feelings. I know.
我觉得很抱歉
I felt so awful about that.
知道吗  路易  你是该抱歉的
You know what, Louis? You should.
并且  你也该为你现在对我犯浑
And while you're at it, you should feel pretty awful
感到抱歉
about being a dick to me right now.
可是你又骗了我
You lied to me again.
我没有  路易  我是又为你争取了一次
No, Louis. I fought for you...again.
你没有
No.
你把琼说得很重要
You made Joan sound important.
"哈维成为冠名合伙人的时候
"The first client that Jessica gave Harvey
"杰西卡给他的第一位客户"
when he made name partner."
她的确很重要  路易  但是你看不到
She is important, Louis, but you can't see that
因为你想要的不是客户
because you didn't want a client.
而是从哈维那里夺走些什么
You just wanted to take something away from Harvey.
我要的是尊重
What I want is respect.
那就别再一意孤行了
Then get out of your own way
加入我们  跟我们合作
and get on the goddamn team.
你是说那个瞒着我迈克秘密的小团体吗
You mean the team that kept Mike's secret from me?
不  路易
No, Louis!
我是指那个会保护成员的团队
I mean the team that protected its own,
因为团队就应该这样
because that's what teams do.
而且  我本不应该告诉你
And, you know, I shouldn't even be telling you this
因为她没打算告诉你
because she wasn't going to,
但是如果你需要更多的证据
but if you need a little bit more evidence
来看我们会为队友做什么
of what we do for each other,
那就看看瑞秋
then take a look at Rachel,
因为她给卡特里娜找了份工作
because she got Katrina a job.
-什么  -正是
- What? - That's right.
你之前的律师
Your former associate,
但是你却对瑞秋肆意践踏
and you've been treating Rachel like shit.
所以  如果你吼够我了
So, if you're done yelling at me,
我建议你在最近搞砸的那么多事里挑一个
then I suggest you go fix one of the thousand things
好好弥补一下
that you have screwed up lately,
因为我们已经不想再为你争取什么了
because the rest of us, we are done fighting for you.
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross.
你肯定是伊安了
Ah, you must be Ian.
千万别叫我罗斯先生
And, please, don't call me Mr. Ross.
-叫迈克就好  -没问题
- Mike is fine. - Ah, sure.
多谢来电  迈克
Hey, thanks for your call, Mike.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特是家很棒的律所
Pearson Specter is a great firm.
你也是个很棒的候选者
Ah, well, you're a great candidate.
我很好奇为什么你还在面试
I'm a little curious why you're still interviewing.
我听说斯卡登确定要雇你了
I heard you had a solid offer at Skadden.
对  但斯卡登-阿布斯不是皮尔逊-斯佩克特
I do, but Skadden Arps is no Pearson Specter.
你确定不是因为
Are you sure it's not because
你担心他们会发现你挂了
you're worried they'll find out that you failed
吉拉德教授的法律职业道德课
Professor Gerard's legal ethics class?
-什么  -我去
- What? - Oh, shit.
你不知道啊
You don't know.
他收了你的两万五千块
He hasn't changed your grade,
但没有给你改成绩
but he still has your $25,000.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我的确有跟你说的那个身份
I'm exactly who I said I was.
没有跟你说的身份是
The only thing I left out is that
吉拉德教授是我的客户
Professor Gerard is my client.
他不可能因为这事惹祸上身
Well, he can't be in trouble for this.
我很清楚
I'd know.
不是这个
He's not.
他被指控在执行联邦仲裁期间
He's being accused of accepting a bribe
收受贿赂
while conducting a federal mediation
就因为这事
because of this.
那不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
现在是你的问题了
It's your problem now,
所以你得签了这个
which is why you're gonna sign this.
那是什么
What is that?
是份誓言证词
It's a sworn affidavit
说明你给吉拉德的钱是借款
stating the money that you paid Gerard is a loan.
那我的成绩怎么办
Well, what happens to my grade?
保持原样  因为亨利·吉拉德
It stays the same because Henry Gerard
没有收钱改成绩
doesn't take money to change grades.
胡说八道  我们有协议
That's bullshit. We had a deal.
把这看作你在现实世界的第一课吧
Yeah, well, consider this your first lesson in the real world.
协议会有变
Deals change.
我不管什么世界
I don't care what world it is.
反正我什么也不签
I'm not signing anything.
那太糟了
That's too bad,
因为那样  事实会被披露
because the truth will come out.
照我的办法  你只是挂门课
And this way, you're failing a class
而不会因贿赂教授
instead of getting thrown out of school
而被丢出学校
for bribing a professor.
全任你选了  伊安
It's up to you, Ian.
你想收下一个不及格成绩
You want an F,
还是彻底丢掉法律职业生涯
or do you want to not have a legal career at all?
我签了这个  贿赂指控就没了吗
So I sign this, and the bribery allegations are gone?
也没人会知道
And no one ever knows a thing.
但我还得把钱还给伊安
But I still have to pay Ian back the money.
借款就是这样
That's the way loans work.
你说话的语气好像我是怪物
You say that like I am a monster.
我的语气是说那是事实
I say it like it's true.
你知道吗...
You know...
你从没让我说明钱是做什么的
you never let me tell you what the money was for.
你没听懂  我说过我不在乎
You didn't listen to me when I told you I don't care.
那谁是怪物呢
Who's the monster now?
我不在乎是因为你总说
I don't care because you always said
背景情况并不重要
the circumstances don't matter.
那你在乎迈克盘问我之后
Well, do you care that after Mike grilled me,
我对他印象深刻
I was so impressed with him
好奇我为什么会忘记他吗
that I wonder why I'd forgotten him.
于是我去看了旧档案
So I looked through my old records,
想看看他成绩怎么样
just to see how he did,
但找不到任何关于他
but I couldn't find any record of him
听我课的记录
ever being in my class.
就像他们也不会找到任何
Just like they're not gonna find any record
关于你收学生贿赂的记录一样
of you accepting a bribe from a student.
你是说我们扯平了吗
You saying we're even?
我说你这回一箭双雕
I'm saying you got a two-for-one,
因为他们也不会找到任何
because they're also not gonna find any record
你去年赌博的记录
of you gambling last year.
所以你那次找我是为这个  对吗
That's why you came to see me back then, isn't it?
你不希望任何人发现他的情况
You didn't want anyone to find out about him.
我不会告诉你我去年找你
I'm not gonna tell you why I came
是为了什么  亨利
to see you last year, Henry,
因为背景情况不重要
because the circumstances don't matter.
你确实好好听我的课了
You really did pay attention in my class.
比你认为的认真多了
A lot more than you think.
很抱歉我让你失望了  斯佩克特先生
I'm sorry I let you down, Mr. Specter.
教授...
Professor...
不用担心还钱的事
don't worry about paying back that loan.
我来搞定
I got it.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
路易
Louis...
有什么需要我帮忙
what can I do for you?
问题不是我要你帮什么忙  杰夫
The question isn't what you can do for me, Jeff,
而是你要怎么做
but it's a matter of what you're gonna do,
也就是告诉你不要胡说八道
which is cut the bullshit right now.
-什么  -你听到了
- What? - You heard me.
我知道杰西卡告诉你哈德曼的事了
I know Jessica told you about Hardman.
是  她是告诉我了
Yeah, she did tell me,
我也出于礼貌  扼制了自己
and I have refrained from coming to see you
没有因为你勒索她而去找你
about blackmailing her out of courtesy.
礼貌
Courtesy?
你都没有祝福恭喜我
You haven't so much as wished me a congratulations.
你还想让我祝贺你上位[吻你戒指]  路易
You want me to kiss the ring, Louis,
在你做了那些事情之后
after what you did?
说得对  我做了
You're damn right I do,
因为我不在乎上位的手段
because I don't care how it got up there.
我的名字现在在墙上
My name is on that wall.
如果我现在有根撬棍
And if I had a crowbar handy...
就亲手把它撬下来
I would pry it off.
杰夫  你没有撬棍
Well, Jeff, you don't.
所以你该问自己的问题是
So the question you got to ask yourself is,
"你想继续在团队里吗"
"Do you want to stick with the team?"
因为我的名字就在墙上
Because my name is up there to stay
无论你喜欢与否
whether you like it or not.
多谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting me.
怎么了
What's going on?
我想谢谢你让我接了吉拉德的案子
I wanted to thank you for making me take Gerard.
出什么事了
What happened?
你为什么会觉得出事了
What makes you think something happened?
因为我了解你
Because I know you,
我知道你不会做自我反思
and I know you don't have moments of self-reflection,
更不会跑出来跟人喝酒告诉他你反思了
let alone have a drink with someone to tell them about it
除非出了事
unless something happened.
是有事
You know what? Something did happen.
我处理了件烂事
I dealt with some shit,
我想为此谢谢你
and I'm trying to thank you for it
因为烂事结果变成了好事
because it turned out to be a good thing.
我觉得你想说的词是"终结"
I think the word you're looking for is "Closure."
那是你的词
That's your word.
我想说的是
The word I'm looking for is,
"不客气  哈维
"You're welcome, Harvey.
"很高兴听到你说这个"
That's nice of you to say."
谢谢  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
很好
Good.
你听我说
Now listen to me.
有那么一瞬间  我以为
For a minute there, I thought
你要告诉我他知道了
you were gonna tell me that he knows.
知道什么
What?
也许是我偏执
Maybe I'm crazy,
但我帮他准备证词时  有次他看着我
but when I was prepping him, for a second, he looked at me,
而我在想
and I thought,
"他怀疑我了"
"He's suspicious."
之后你又打电话
And then you called,
在发生这么多事之后  我...
and after everything that's happened already, I--
没事  迈克  他不知道
It's fine, Mike. He doesn't know.